ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
电脑团
小酸奶!
翻译
吃冰棒
时间轴
大葱ALX  念念
电脑狂人
第四季
第六集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
豪伊全知道
卡梅伦·豪伊画廊
爷爷早日康复
爱你  萨姆
去清风房车了得想事情亲亲  卡
凯瑟琳·J·豪伊
早上好
Good morning.
我想出来了  "去看彗星"
I got it: "Catch the Comet."
-不好  -为什么
- No. - Why not?
因为听上去好像在说流感
Because it sounds like the flu.
或是阴虱
Or the clap.
"一起彗星"怎么样
How 'bout,  "let's Comet"?
不如还是  算了吧
How 'bout, let's not.
就像棉签  纸巾  创可贴一样
It's like Q-tip, Kleenex, Band-Aid --
我们能成为第一个互联网品牌
We could be the first Internet brand.
是啊  我也很乐意做你的焦点小组
Yes, and I would love to be your focus group.
只不过得在10点后
Just after 10:00 A.M.
但流浪者正脆弱  少了一个经理...
But Rover's vulnerable, one manager down...
乔
Joe.
别这样  太邪恶了
Come on. That's a little evil.
只是个玩笑
It's a joke.
放松
Relax.
我想尽早跟你一起去看看他
Hey, I-I want us to visit him soon, okay?
他知道我告诉你了  他很难过
He knows I told you, and he feels bad...
我觉得他想道歉
I think he wants to apologize.
没必要
There's no need.
我们还是有更好的思路
We still have a better approach.
现在发现
And as it turns out,
他们的新搜索算法背后的"天才"
the "genius" behind their new search algorithm
他们根本不能用
is unavailable to them...
奶酪蛋
Cheese egg?
"搜索  查找  会心[彗星]"
"Search it, find it... com-it."
太完美了
It's perfect.
谢谢你能来
Thanks for coming in.
我觉得还是应该面对面
I thought it was important that we speak face to face --
私下聊聊
and in private.
流浪者的代码有90%是我写的
I wrote ninety percent of the code Rover's built on.
没错  它还是一家医学索引公司的时候
Yes, back when it was a medical indexing company.
但流浪者与时俱进
But Rover's evolved,
而你却还在原地踏步
and you haven't evolved with it.
你要我做的事我都做了
I've done everything you've asked me to do.
为什么还得让我走
Why am I the one that has to go?
博斯已经离开了
Bos has already stepped away.
老实说  你的价位更...
And frankly, your deal is much more --
是我和我的朋友一起创立了这家公司
I made this company with my friends.
你觉得我在乎什么离职待遇吗
Do you think I give a shit about an exit package?!
在你跑来  要求我们
We were fine until you came in
完成各种不可能的任务前  我们都好好的
and started demanding the impossible.
如果我之前对你太严苛  对不起
If I've been hard on you, I'm sorry.
但这无关公平
But this isn't about what's fair.
这只关乎生存
This is about survival.
我觉得你不在乎钱
I don't think you care about the money.
但我觉得你在乎你的朋友
But I do think you care about your friends.
事实上  因为将别人的劳动成果据为己有
The fact is, by passing someone else's work off as your own,
你让他们处于了危险之中
you've put them in a precarious position.
唯一能保护他们的办法
The only way to protect them
就是拆分算法
is to take the search algorithm apart
建立流浪者专有的搜索引擎
and build Rover's own proprietary version of it.
要做到这一点  你就不能插手
And for that to work, you can't be involved.
我知道这种  失败的感觉
I do know what it's like, to feel like a failure.
觉得自己没本事
To feel like you don't measure up.
但如果你不离开
But if you don't step aside
让我找其他人
and let me bring in someone else,
你和你朋友可能最终一无所有
you and your friends could end up with noing.
那我该怎么和他们说
So what do I tell them?
真话
The truth.
我累了
I'm burned out.
我这段时间很难熬
I've been struggling for a while now.
流浪者前景不错
Rover's in a good place.
我觉得我也应该向前看了
I feel it's time for me to move on...
试试吧
Try it.
我累了
I'm burned out.
我这段时间很难熬
It's been hard for a while now,
我觉得应该向前看了
and I think it's time to move on...
现在就说
Now...?
需要多久都行
Take all the time you need.
海莉
Haley!
快过来
Get over here!
怎么了  老爸
What is it, Dad?
有件非常重要的事情
Well, we have something really important
我们需要谈谈
that we need to discuss.
好吧
Okay.
我想你知道我要说什么
I think you know what I'm talking about.
并不知道
No. Uh...
火箭
Rockets!
不是吧
No. Way!
-生日快乐  亲爱的  -今天下午就去吧
- Happy birthday, Bug. - Let's go this afternoon!
慢着  今天不行
Well, slow down. We can't.
我们还得把网站重新归类  而且大家
We still have to recategorize the site, and everyone's --
可是天气多好啊  能见度这么高
But the weather's perfect, visibility's awesome!
-海莉别闹  -而且今天真是我的生日
- Haley, come on. - And today's my actual birthday.
可是如果周六去的话  还能邀请你朋友来
Yeah, but if we go Saturday, we can invite your friends.
我现在就问他们
I'll ask them right now.
不  你在学校的朋友
No, your school friends, okay?
他们还得工作  再说了  这是你生日
They have to work. Besides, it's your birthday.
又不是全国假期
It's not a national holiday.
好吧  那邀请凯蒂去行吗
Okay, well, what about inviting Katie?
真的
Really?
是啊  求你了  去吧  就咱们几个
Yeah, c'mon, let's do it. Just us.
我看看能不能联系上卡梅
Let me see if I can reach Cam.
我问问她能不能腾出点时间来
I'll check to see if she can move up the day.
你最棒了
You're the best!
还没完全确定哟
It's not 100%!
真不像是西塞尔会做的事
This is just so unlike Cecil.
这种人员调整是难免的事
Look, shake-ups like this happen.
在我看来  这事无论是对你们
As far as I'm concerned, it's no refection on you
还是对流浪者的长期发展都没有影响
or on the long-term viability of Rover.
但这难道不会引发议论吗
But this will raise eyebrows, won't it?
一个创始人
I-I mean, for a cofounder
在公司势头正好的时候退出
to leave when the company's doing so well --
相信我  大家唯一关心的事
Trust me, the only thing anyone cares about
就是我们有多少流量
is how much traffic we're getting.
而在这个方面  谭雅说得对
And in that respect, Tanya's right.
我们真的势头很好
We're doing really well.
而且有了首轮融资  我们就有机会
And with the Series A, we have the opportunity
吸引更厉害的优秀人才
to attract some formidable talent.
我要你们把精力放在优化网站上
I want you guys to focus on optimizing the site.
而我来主持人才引进的事
And I'll take lead on hiring
确保我们能把硅谷最优秀的首席技术官请来
and make sure we land the best CTO in the Valley.
现在还有能人闲着吗
Is anyone good even available?
有啊  博比·阿伦
Yeah, Bobby Aron is.
博比·阿伦
Bobby Aron?
你开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
这个人  是个传说
That guy's a -- a legend.
微软花了大工夫想请他去
Microsoft's making a huge play for him.
我真的觉得
I really don't think --
听我说
Listen to me.
我们业内领先
We're the big ones.
任何人能来我们这里当技术官  是他命好
Any CTO would be lucky to be with us.
从现在起就要拿出领头羊的架子来  明白吗
That's how we operate from now on. Got it?
-好吧  -好
- All right. - Yep.
明白
Got it.
好的
Okay.
看起来如何
How's it look?
挺不错  戈大胖
Nice. El Gordo!
是啊
Yeah.
你知道是什么意思吧
You know what it means, right?
知道  "大帅哥"
Yeah. "Handsome."
没错
Exactly.
你看这个
Hey, you see that?
是海莉画的
Haley drew it.
水手每航行五千英里就文上一个
Sailors get one tattooed for every 5,000 miles.
但你知道她说什么吗
But you know what she said?
因为这火箭是实物缩小一百倍
Since the rocket's 1/100th in scale,
它只要飞五十英里就行
it only needs to cover fifty.
你的还没发射呢  所以
Well, you haven't launched yours yet, so...
你真觉得我不能
What, do you honestly think I'm not gonna launch
让它飞五十英里远
that thing 50 miles?
好吧
Fair enough.
别担心  亲爱的
No, don't worry, hon.
你觉得她不想邀请
Do you think it's weird
她学校里的朋友是不是很奇怪
that she didn't want to invite any of her school friends?
不
No.
学校朋友没那么重要
School friends are overrated.
她看上去很开心
She seems really happy.
而且凯蒂很棒
And Katie is great.
我觉得它少了点什么
I feel like it's missing something...
你是准备发射进入地球轨道吗
Oh, you're planning on going orbital?
这个一定要进入外逸层
Definitely exosphere on this one.
你们经常玩这个吗
You guys do this a lot?
对  我们以前一直玩
Yeah, we used to go all the time
直到我妈炸伤了手
until my mom blew her hand off.
我们当时都没看到它飞过来
It's just... We didn't even see it coming.
-你知道吗  -你太逗了
- You know? - You are hilarious.
在我几乎许诺给你的邻居一个肾之后
So then, after I practically promised her a kidney,
她让她可怜的儿子跑了十英里
your neighbor makes her poor son run ten miles...
一  一英里
One. One mile. ...
就为了去敲你的门给你传消息
just to come and knock on your door and give you a message?
那又怎样  我又不是之后没载他回家
So? It's not like I didn't give him a ride home afterwards.
你知道  电话19世纪就发明出来了
Phones were invented in the 19th century, you know,
当时美国还几乎都是农村
when America was still mostly agrarian.
你可以自己做一个
I mean, you could build your own.
事实上  你应该做一个
In fact, you should.
你太闲的时候
You're a lot of trouble
就是个大麻烦
when you've got too much time on your hands.
我告诉你了  我为了博斯才那么做的
I told you, I did that to help Bos.
他也找我帮忙了
He asked me for help, too,
但我没直接给他写个算法
but I didn't go out and write him an algorithm.
好吧  别担心
Okay, well, don't worry,
我不干了
I'm done.
我厌倦了科技  这所有的一切
I'm sick of tech. The whole thing.
你怎么了  才32就江郎才尽了
What are you, washed up at 32?
别这样  你就得了一个差评啊
Come on. You got one lousy review.
你知不知道大家都是怎么说交响乐的
And do you have any idea what people said about the Symphonic?
我可了解你
Come on, I know you.
你的梦都是代码
You dream in code.
是啊
Yeah.
但现在不是了
Not anymore.
你们快来
Hey, guys!
-快来  -我们准备好了
- Guys, guys. - We're ready!
快来
Come on.
-好  插钥匙  -插了
- All right, get your keys in. - Key's in.
你可以给我录像吗
Would you -- Would you film me?
生日快乐  亲爱的
Happy birthday, Bug.
倒数五下
And T-minus five...
四
Four...
三  二  一
three, two, one...
发射
Blast off!
轰隆
Boom.
它飞去哪了
Where'd it go?
它去哪了
Where is it?!
我应该拦住它的
I'm supposed to stop it!
这是什么  用来自杀的音乐吗
What is this, music to kill yourself by?
你可以给我拿瓶啤酒吗
Hey, would you mind bringing me a beer?
如果你想也可以来一瓶
You can have one too, if you want.
别告诉你爸
Don't tell your dad.
博斯如何了
So how's Bos?
还行吧
Good, I think.
你第一次尝啤酒是什么感觉
And how's your first sip of beer?
很难喝
It's awful.
不过他没事了吧  他昨天就出院了吧
But he's good, right? They released him yesterday?
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
我周五放学后去看他了
I saw him Friday, after school.
我以为医院探视时间是早上
I thought visiting hours at the hospital were in the morning.
我跟他们说我是他的孙女
I told them I was his granddaughter.
我爱死你这一点了
I love that about you.
你知道的  对吗
You know that, right?
你真的特别无畏
You're absolutely fearless.
那是医院
It's a hospital.
他们又不会逮捕我
They're not gonna arrest me.
真不知道你像谁
Well, I don't know where you get it.
你从来没闯过祸吗
You never got in any trouble?
做过什么疯狂的事
Do anything crazy?
我这人很谨慎...
I was pretty cautious...
得了吧
C'mon.
说说嘛
你爸和我以前经常去野营
Well... your dad and I used to go camping all the time,
有一次我们到了一个营地
and we went to this one campsite.
那里的当地人总是说起他们会去的一个采石场
And the locals always talked about this quarry they'd go to.
那里有个天然泳池
It was a swimming hole.
所以你爸和我开车去找到了那个天然泳池
So your dad and I drove out there, and we found it.
那里非常美
It was incredible.
我们站在一个悬崖上俯瞰着底下
It was this cliff overlooking
最最清澈  透亮  湛蓝的池水
the glassiest, clearest blue water you've ever seen.
你爸爸不敢跳下去
And your dad wouldn't jump in.
他不敢  太高了
He wouldn't. It was too high.
所以我嘲笑他
So I laughed at him,
他说  "我赌你也不敢"
and he said, "I bet you won't, either."
于是我不假思索地冲到悬崖边
So before I could think twice, I ran right up to the edge,
一个空翻跳了下去
did a cartwheel right off.
我的天呐  妈
Holy shit, Mom,
我能生下来都算是个奇迹了
it's a miracle that I was even born.
我猜我当时就是不相信
I guess I just didn't believe
我会受伤  知道吗
that I could really get hurt, you know?
我就是感觉很自由
It just felt...free.
你的心也很自由
You have that,
我希望你永远别变
and I don't ever want you to lose it.
永远别因为害怕就畏缩不前
Don't ever stop yourself 'cause you're scared...
好吧
Okay.
那下次我闯了祸  你要记住
Well, next time I get in trouble, remember:
那是因为我勇敢
It's 'cause I'm being "brave."
好吧
All right.
我要去写作业了
I got to do my homework, so...
好
All right.
晚安
G'night.
这真不可思议  不是吗
It's amazing, isn't it?
前一刻  海莉才四岁
One minute, Haley's four
用沙发垫盖了一个堡垒
and building a fort out of the sofa cushions.
下一刻  她就已经...
The next minute, she's...
我在捏爆你的头
I'm crushing your head.
说着《少年监狱》中的笑话
...telling "Kids in the Hall" jokes.
真是太酷了
It's just...so cool.
是啊  小孩都很可爱
Oh, yeah, kids are great --
如果你能直接生出个14岁的孩子
if you can give birth to a fourteen-year-old.
晚上见
I will see you tonight.
再见
Bye.
这是什么...
What the hell...?
好了  放松
All right, just relax.
清空思绪
Clear your mind.
怂包
Coward.
说到"互联网"
Okay, uh, the first thing that I think of
我首先想到的是...
when I hear "Internet" is...
电脑
A computer?
A computer.
-还有毛片  -毛片
- And porn. - Porn.
-毛片  -一堆毛片
- Porn? - Lots of porn.
我想加入给毛片分类的团队
I put in a request to be on the team that catalogues porn.
哔  哔  哔
Beep, beep, beep...
戈登·克拉克
Gordon Clark.
是我
Hey, it's me.
抱歉通知得这么晚
I'm sorry this is so last second,
但晚饭能改期吗
but can we reschedule dinner?
没问题
Yeah, no problem.
反正也没有什么要报告的
N-Nothing to report anyway.
其实有
Well, actually, there is.
海莉的辅导老师打电话给我了
I got a phone call from Haley's guidance counselor.
她历史和生物都要挂科了
She's flunking history and bio.
我们的女儿海莉吗
Our Haley?
是  她有些作业没交
Yeah, she hasn't turned in some assignments,
最近几次考试也都挂了
and apparently she bombed the last couple tests...
我不明白  她成绩那么好
I don't get it, she was doing so great...
可能她就是分身乏术
Well, maybe she's just trying to do too much.
别这样  唐娜  她那么喜欢彗星
Come on, Donna. She loves Comet.
我知道她很喜欢  但我觉得她该缓缓
I know she loves it, but I think she needs a break.
我担心她把工作放在首位了
I'm afraid she's putting work above everything else.
也不知道是跟谁学的
Well, I wonder where she gets that from.
你在开玩笑吧  我总是把孩子放在工作前面
Excuse me. I always put the girls before work.
如果你想让我去和海莉谈
And if you need me to talk to Haley
因为你自己搞不定  那...
because you can't handle it, then --
我很抱歉  好吗
I-I -- I'm sorry, all right?
我只是...
I just...
我不想唱黑脸
I don't want to be the bad guy here.
你以为我想吗
And I do?
好吧  我会和她谈的
Okay, I'll talk to her.
谢谢  戈登
Thank you, Gordon.
怎么了
Whassup?
这地方不错
Uh, it's a nice place.
-很有趣  -感谢你停车  我都饿坏了
- It's...charming. - Yeah, thanks for stopping. I was staved.
你最喜欢的网站是什么
So...favorite site?
天哪  没法选  太难选了
God, I can't pick just one -- That's too hard!
其他人都选什么
What did everyone else say?
有个人最喜欢的网站
Well, one person's favorite site
是全紫的屏幕
was a purple screen.
就那么简单  紫屏
Just that -- a purple screen.
是梅莉莎吧
Melissa, right?
她沉迷于此
She's obsessed.
还有人推荐了
And someone else recommended
"草莓馅饼喷灯"
"Strawberry Pop Tart Blowtorches."
对  是阿尼发现的
Oh, yeah, Arnie found that one!
我们一整天都在给馅饼点火
We spent an entire day setting Pop-Tarts on fire.
我们大概弄坏了三个烤面包机
I think we destroyed like three toasters.
真厉害
That's impressive.
但我不知道这些东西
But I'm not sure how any of these
怎么吸引普通人
are gonna get the average person online.
为什么不能呢  我就是这样开始上网的
Why not? They got me online.
怎么会
How so?
我刚开始浏览互联网的时候
Well, when I first looked at the Internet --
还记得你的便条吗
Remember your Post-its? --
我那时觉得很无聊
I thought it was pretty boring.
就是一堆数据库和文档
It was nothing but databases and archives...
但后来我就发现了一些其他的东西
But then I found all this other stuff --
比如有个孩子  贾斯汀  会写生活日记
like this kid, Justin, who's writing about his life.
还有一个女孩
And this other girl
痴迷于《我爱露西》...
who was obsessed with "I Love Lucy"...
这些东西吸引人的地方在哪里
And what about that was so appealing?
我也不知道
I don't know.
上学很没劲
School was not good.
倒不是有人欺负我什么的
I mean, no one was torturing me or anything like that,
只是  大家都在装
but it's just, like, everyone's always pretending,
懂吗
you know?
所以互联网才很棒  因为没人假装
That's why the Web's so great, 'cause no one pretends.
你会展现真实的自己
You just put it out there, who you really are.
如果有人回应  那很好
And if people respond to it, that's great.
但即使没有  又如何
But if not, who cares?
至少他们看到的是你
At least they saw you
不是一个投影
and not just some projection, you know?
嗯
Yeah.
你们在工作吗
You guys working?
是啊  你好  凡妮莎
Yeah. Hi, Vanessa.
这是我老板  乔·麦克米伦
This is my boss, Joe MacMillan.
其实  是联合创始人
Actually, cofounder.
厉害
Cool.
我超级喜欢互联网地下音乐档案
I'm totally addicted to IUMA, by the way.
他们的独立摇滚版块  太棒了
Their indie rock section's, like, incredible --
是啊  谁还需要地下流行乐
I know. It's like who needs Sub Pop?
你找到冰薄荷酒的那版编曲了吗
Did you find that Julep compilation?
就是混音了幼童车歌曲的那个
The one with the Bratmobile song?
嗯
Yes!
我们谈谈...
"Let's talk about...
-狗吧  -狗
- dogs." - Dogs.
-是啊  -是啊
- Yeah. -Yeah.
贝茜天堂的歌也太酷了
The Heavens to Betsy song's, like, hella cool, too.
是啊
Yeah.
我得回去上班了  但回见了
I better get back to work, but I'll see you later.
好啊
Yeah. For sure.
好
Cool.
她挺不错
She seems cool.
我们刚刚说什么来着
What were we talking about again?
在互联网上
So on the Internet...
你觉得你可以做真实的自己
you think you can be who you really are?
流浪者不仅能计算用户数量
With Rover we cannot only count the number of users,
还能追踪他们的浏览和浏览时间
we can track what they click on, how long they look at it --
这是广告人的美梦
I mean, it's an advertiser's dream.
那么是推销咯
So, it is about selling.
不...
No, it's
重点是改变
It's about change.
在流浪者  你可以加入
At Rover, you could be part
一个全球化的分散的平台
of a universal, decentralized platform
而且它已经在改变世界了
that's already changing the world.
你可以加入微软
Look. You could join Microsoft
让他们来给你定义未来
and let them tell you what the future will be.
你也可以加入我们  自己定义未来
Or you could join us and tell them.
我今早已经接受微软的邀约了
I accepted the Microsoft offer this morning.
我没有推掉会面是因为  我小时候
I only kept this meeting because, well, growing up,
是穆特尼的大粉丝
I was a huge fan of Mutiny --
准确说是社区
really Community.
我结交了朋友
I-I made friends,
还交易了商品
and I traded bootlegs
买卖电脑部件
and bought and sold computer parts.
那挽救了我  真的
It was a lifesaver, really.
我
And I, uh...
我猜我就是想谢谢你
Well, I guess I just wanted to thank you.
我很高兴
That's really nice to hear, but I
但我真心希望能成的
I was really hoping this would work out.
我能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
社区是那么超前于时代
Community was so far ahead of its time.
你为什么一直没试着重建它
Why haven't you tried to re-create it?
穆特尼是我最快乐的时光
Mutiny was the most fun I ever had.
我们当时就是毫无章法
We didn't know what we were doing.
一个个地解决危机
It was one crisis after another.
但它成功了
But it worked.
它后来的失败
The failure of that was...
怎么说的来着
Well, what's that saying --
断掉的地方会长得更结实
You grow stronger at the broken places...?
不说了
Anyway.
事实上
Yeah, the truth is,
我是想再建立一版社区
I am trying to build another version of Community.
但这次是整个互联网了
Except, this time, it's the entire Internet.
是所有人
It's everyone.
这就是流浪者最了不起的地方
That's what's so exciting about Rover.
它不设保护地
It's flying without a net
飞入了未知
into the great unknown.
很吓人  也很令人兴奋
It's terrifying, and it's exhilarating.
好吧
Well...
我以前也是改过主意的
I have been known to change my mind, though.
嗯
Yeah.
微软很安全
Microsoft's safe.
但是  怎么说的来着
But, um, well, what's that saying?
没有危险  就没有奖赏嘛
No risk, no reward, right?
我加入
I'm in.
如果你还想要我的话
If you still want me, that is.
当然了
I-I -- Y-- Absolutely!
那好
Okay, okay.
我可能需要你凌厉的一面帮忙
I might need your shark side to help me out, though.
微软可绝不会喜欢这样的
The Beast of Redmond ain't gonna like this one bit.
我才不怕他们
They don't scare me.
是啊  我猜你谁都不怕
Yeah, I can't imagine who would.
敬危险
To risk.
你想再来吗
You up for one more?
你好
Hello.
你还好吗
Feeling okay...?
嗯
Yeah.
有咖啡
There's coffee...
我该...走了
I should, uh -- I should get going.
我们该...
Yeah, we should, um...
谈谈工作的事
We should talk about the job --
其实
You know...
算了
it's fine.
嗯
Yeah.
好吧
O-Okay.
约翰
John?
是萨姆寄来的
It's from Sam.
那个头发浓密的是我
That's me with all the hair.
真是个好孩子
What a kid.
约翰  这整件事
John, this whole experience...
让我开始思考
it's been making me think.
在医院  情况很糟
At the hospital, it was so hard.
我根本无权决定你的治疗
I had no say in your care
要是真出了事
and if something had gone wrong...
但没事嘛
Yeah, but it didn't.
我没事
I'm fine...
不仅是这个
Well, it's not just that.
在餐厅  有那么一刻
At the restaurant, there was a moment...
你的样子
the way you looked.
我以为自己要失去你了
I thought I was losing you.
我爱你
I love you.
我不知道我们还剩多少时间能在一起
And I don't know how much time together we have left.
那我们还等什么
So what're we waiting for?
我没有戒指
Now, I don't have a ring --
我知道你想要颗大钻石
And I know you're expecting a big rock...
女人啊  你要我的心怎么承受得来
Goddamn, woman, what're you doing to my heart?
怎么样
So...?
记得帕特森房屋开发吗
Do you remember the Patterson housing development?
你没参加
You passed on it.
但我觉得还是值得考虑的
I thought it was worth a second look.
赔了多少
How much?
30万
300k.
我想自己解决
I wanted to take care of it myself.
我不希望你知道我多傻
I didn't want you to know what a fool I was --
我以为去流浪者工作能双赢
I thought workin' at Rover would be a win-win,
结果  我们遇上了障碍  我慌了
and then we started hitting a wall, and I panicked.
你看到之前的网站了  根本不够好
You saw the site. It wasn't good enough.
我们跳不过那个障碍
We couldn't get over that hump.
所以我去找卡梅帮忙建了搜索引擎
So I-I got Cam to help build the search engine.
唐娜发现了
And Donna found out,
在餐厅时  她知道...
and then at restaurant, she knew that she --
对不起
I'm sorry.
黛安
Diane.
Diane!
海莉  过来
Haley? C'mere.
怎么了  皮特还在等着送我回学校
What is it? Pete's waiting to take me back to school.
我们得谈谈你的成绩
We need to talk about your grades.
好吧
Okay...
学校来电话了
The school called.
-说你挂了两科  -挂科
- They said that you're failing two classes. - Failing?
我可能是错过了几次测试  但我还可以重考
I -- Maybe I missed a few tests, but I can just retake them.
-这个嘛  -我可以去找我的老师谈
- Well... - I'll talk to my teacher. I can...
我们说好  你在这里工作
We agreed that you could work here
前提是能保持成绩
if you kept up your grades.
那是我们说好的
That was the deal.
你什么意思  我得停止工作吗
S-So what're you saying? I have to stop working?
暂时的  直到你恢复成绩
Just temporarily until you can bring your grades back up,
到时可以再考虑
and then we can talk --
但是  爸爸  这是海莉的彗星
But, Dad -- It's Haley's Comet!
要不是我  你根本没有这间公司
You wouldn't even have a company if weren't for me!
听着  冷静点  亲爱的
Hey, listen. Calm down, Bug.
-并不完全是这样的  -别再喊我"亲爱的"了
- That's not entirely accurate. - Stop calling me "Bug"!
我还何必去上学
And why do I even need school?
我已经有工作了
I already have a job.
因为你需要去上学学习
Because you need school to learn
-结交朋友  -我的朋友都在这里
- and to make friends - My friends are here --
你不能解雇我  他们需要我
And you can't fire me, they need me!
好吧  我觉得我们还是能撑住的
Okay, well, I think we'd be able to manage --
海莉  去收拾
Haley, clean it up.
-不  -海莉  如果你还想回来工作
- No. - Haley, if you ever want to work here again,
你就去给我收拾
you will clean. It. Up.
海莉
Haley!
海...
Ha--
给我回来
Get back here!
海莉
Haley!
看什么
What?!
是啊  红皮钱包
Yes, it's a red leather wallet.
我当时坐在吧台
I was siting at the bar...
是吗
You do?
我今晚去拿  谢谢
I-I will come by tonight. Thank you.
有时间吗
Do you have a moment?
怎么了
What's going on...?
我跟约翰谈了
I had a talk with John.
显然  他做了些跟流浪者有关的
And apparently he's made some bad decisions
错误决定
regarding Rover.
但我想你已经知道了
But I think you already know that.
我是有所怀疑
Well, I had my suspicions,
但我并不确定  直到我看见了卡梅
but I didn't know for sure until I saw Cam...
都结束了
It's done.
重要的是
Now, the important thing
解决麻烦  继续向前
is to clean up the mess and move on.
我非常同意  西塞尔已经走了
I couldn't agree more. Cecil is gone.
我们打算找一个人
We plan to find someone
来逆向工程流浪者的代码
who can reverse engineer Rover's code --
逆向工程  为什么
Reverse engineer? Why?
避免网站承担法律责任
Oh, to protect the site from any liabilities --
但如果是卡梅伦写了代码
But if Cameron built this code,
接下来  唯一的办法
the next step -- the only step --
就是让她签转让书
is to get her to sign a release.
只有这样才能保护网站
That's how we protect the site.
是啊
Yes, yes.
但在这件事上
But in this one case,
我真心认为这不是合适的办法
I really think that is the wrong move.
何必让卡梅伦知道
I mean, why let Cameron know
她给我们的东西多宝贵
how valuable what she gave us was?
最好还是创造我们自己版本的算法
I mean, better to just create our own version of the algorithm,
反正也没人会知道
and no one will be any wiser.
这毫无道理
That doesn't make any sense.
现在有个简单的办法
Look, there is one simple solution,
而且早该去做了
and it should've happened immediately:
付给卡梅伦她索要的费用  然后了事
pay Cameron whatever she wants and be done with it.
不行  我做不到
No! I can't. I can't.
我就是
I-I just...
做不到
I-I can't.
接下来要这么办
Well, this is what's gonna happen.
你要去找卡梅伦
You're going to go to Cameron
让她签转让书
and get her to sign a release.
然后你要让位
And then you will step away.
让崔普接手
And Trip will take over.
我...
Th-- I...
这不公平
That's not fair.
他...你了解他的
He'll just -- He'll -- You know him.
-他会利用这机会  -成为执行合伙人吗
- He'll use it! - To become managing partner?
或许吧
Perhaps.
或许这样最好
Maybe that's best.
老实说  你有更严重的问题
Frankly, you have bigger issues to deal with.
自己振作点吧  唐娜
Get yourself together, Donna.
我不想再照顾着你了
I'm tired of holding your hand.
这一切都是因为
None of this would've happened
博斯觉得没法跟你说实话
if Bos felt like he could just come and talk to you.
我收到你邮件时很意外
I was surprised to get your e-mail.
我都要放弃你了
I was about to give up on you.
是啊
Yeah.
这究竟是什么事啊
So what is this about, exactly?
你...
You, um...
-是雅达利派你来的吗  -不是
- Did Atari send you or - Oh, no.
不过  他们好心给了我
Although they were kind enough
一份《朝圣者》
to give me a copy of "Pilgrim."
-是吗  -只要问得巧  什么都能得到
- They did? - You can get anything if you know how to ask.
我觉得这游戏很有趣
I thought the game was interesting --
有缺点  但有趣
flawed, but interesting.
我从未玩过一个
I mean, I've never played a game
如此努力地设置障碍的游戏
that actively blocks your way so much.
是啊
Yeah.
我...是想尊重玩家
Well, I, uh -- I was trying to respect the gamer.
吸引他们
Engage them,
-不是把他们当作被动的接收者  -是尊重
- not treat them like a passive receptacle, but - Respect, sure,
但你显然不希望任何人破解游戏
but you clearly didn't want anyone to solve the game.
我不知道为什么  那是你的怪癖
Why, I have no idea. That's your thing.
但你创建来容纳谜题的世界
But the world that you created to contain the puzzles,
那个很有趣
that was interesting.
图像也很棒
And the graphics were incredible.
我相信这跟你的设想
I'm sure they still don't even come close
还是相去甚远
to what you saw in your head.
能满足我设想的电脑还没发明呢
Well, the computer for that doesn't exist yet.
真的吗
You sure?
处理器的速度在以指数增长
Processor speed is growing at an exponential rate.
我见到了现在的发展  令人震撼
I've seen what's happening, and it's mind-blowing.
因为问题是
'Cause here's the thing:
我不认为你是个游戏设计者
I don't think you're a game designer.
我认为你是个世界构建者
I think you're a world builder.
我想跟你合作
And I'd like to work with you.
我想看看你接下来要做什么
I want to see what you do next.
好吧
Okay.
那我为什么要想跟你合作
And why should I want to work with you?
因为我的条件是
Because here's what I'm offering:
不拉风投  不做干预
no VCs. No interference.
你在门罗互联网战略会议上说的话很对
What you said at MISC was spot on:
这个模式有问题
The model is broken.
是寄生关系
Parasitic.
所以我不打算妨碍你
So I plan to stay out of your way.
那我做什么呢
While I do what, exactly?
随你便
Whatever you want.
你没事吧
You okay?
嗯
Yup.
-想谈谈吗  -不
- You wanna talk? - Nope.
猎狗热狗
Hound Dogz.
我们昨天刚去过
We were just there yesterday.
嗯  她可喜欢那里了
Yep. She loves that place.
真不知为什么  那里食物好烂
No idea why, the food sucks.
或许不是为了食物
Maybe it's not about the food.
她什么时候回来
When's she coming back?
不知道  她不在这里工作了
No idea. She no longer works here.
你做了什么  解雇她吗
What did you do, fire her?
我让她选  她却走人了
I gave her a choice, and she walked.
那就把她找回来
So get her back.
乔  她在挂科
Joe, she's flunking her classes
而且态度很有问题
and copping some major attitude.
你不懂  海莉需要这里
You don't understand, Haley needs this place.
她跟其他孩子不一样
She's not like other kids.
她有不一样的
She's got different, um...
兴趣
interests.
好啊
Well, good for her.
她有点像我
She's a little like me.
我小时候
When I was a kid,
非常渴望有这样的地方
I would've given anything for a place like this,
一个让我有归属感的地方
someplace I could feel like I belonged.
是吗  做家长就是这样
Yeah? Well, this is what parenting is.
设下界线  始终一致  管教孩子
Setting limits, being consistent, and discipline.
你口气像我爸
You sound like my dad.
别拿我跟你爸爸比
Don't even start to compare me to your father
因为我们不是一个宇宙的
because the two of us are not even in the same universe.
我只是说  他从未真正看到我
All I'm saying is he never really saw me.
他只希望我像他
He just wanted me to be like him.
我是说  我看海莉看得很清楚
All I'm saying is that I see Haley just fine.
好吧  我或许没跟她一起喝过奶昔
Okay, I may not sit around sipping milkshakes with her,
但我很了解我的女儿
but I know exactly who my daughter is.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
这话什么意思
All right, what the hell is that supposed to mean?
没事
Nothing.
我只是想为海莉好
I just want what's best for Haley.
得了  乔
Oh, come on, Joe.
你对她的关心
You don't give a shit about her
仅限于她能为公司贡献什么
beyond what she can do for this company.
你只想为自己好
You just want what's best for you.
所以你不是家长  你也永远不会是
That's why you're not a parent and you never will be.
你说的对
You're right.
你打到哪一级了
What level is that?
两位  学校怎么样
Guys. How was school?
她跟爸爸吵架了
She had a fight with Dad.
你怎么这么早就回家了
What're you doing home so early?
我不舒服
I wasn't feeling well.
翘班  棒
Cutting work. Nice.
我们今天来了个很酷的代课老师
We had a cool sub today.
-是吗  -她是个美国人
- Oh, yeah? - She's American,
但她去法国上的大学
but she went to college in France.
据说  你可以去做
Apparently, you can do, like, some, like,
交换学生
international-student thing,
她说那可棒了
and she said it's, like, it was amazing
她还在法国电影馆看了些电影
and that she saw these films at the Cinémathèque,
还说他们有好多
and that, um, they have all these, like,
很酷的课程  电影  摄影
really cool programs for, like, film and photography, and --
你知道我喜欢你哪点吗  琼妮
Do you know what I love about you, Joanie?
你好...无畏
You are so...fearless.
你知道吗
You know?
我希望你永远别变
I hope you never lose that.
永远别因为害怕就拒绝什么
Just don't ever say no to something because you're scared.
你想来跟我一起玩吗
You want to come play with me?
来吧  我教你诀窍
Come on. I'll show you all my secrets.
不用了
It's okay.
我
I'm gonna, um...
还是去看看海莉在干什么
I'm gonna go check with Haley and see what she's up to.
-好吧  -嗯
- Uh, okay. - Yeah.
你想去哪
Where do you want to go?
喂
Hello?
乔
Joe.
是博斯
Hey, it's Bos.
卡梅伦在吗
Is Cameron there?
不在
No.
抱歉  要留个言吗
Sorry. You want to leave a message?
不了  我
No, no. I'll just...
待会儿再打好了
I'll just call back later.
你还好吗
How're you holding up?
这个嘛
Well...
真是一团糟
What a mess.
我跟自己说  是因为骄傲
Well, I told myself it was pride --
就是愚蠢的骄傲
just stupid pride.
但其实
But the truth is...
我想知道我还有价值
I wanted to know I still mattered,
我想知道我可以做一番大事
wanted to know I could shake things up.
任务达成了
Mission accomplished.
我闯了大祸
They is shook.
是啊
Yeah.
这我可不了解
Well, I wouldn't know anything about that.
我做的那些事
You know, the things that I've done...
我都不知道我为什么那么做
I don't even know why I did them.
我就是想要一切
I just wanted everything,
我不在乎
and I didn't care what
要为此做的任何事
or who I had to go through to get it.
是啊
Yeah.
那家伙
That guy.
真是个混蛋
He was a real asshole.
我好像曾雇过他
I think I hired him once.
或许我还是那种人
Maybe I'm still that guy,
而大家都看得清  只有我看不清
and everybody can see it but me.
不  认清自己是混蛋就已经成功一半了
No. Recognizing you're an asshole is half the battle.
但我见到了你对卡梅多坦诚
But I've seen how honest you've been with Cam.
那跟我最初认识的那个人不一样  乔
That's a different man than the one I first met, Joe.
我自己也需要变变
I could've used some of that myself.
我们都有禁区
Oh, we've got our no-go zones.
是啊  你撒谎  说自己喜欢芭蕾什么的
Well, sure, you lie and say you love the ballet or whatever.
或许  你们中一个想要孩子
Or maybe one of you wants kids,
另一个不想
the other one doesn't
所以你就没说出来
so you just keep it to yourself.
卡梅想要孩子
Cam wants kids?
或许她能让你意外
Well, maybe she'll surprise you.
她或许也能让你意外
She might surprise you, too.
祝你好运
Good luck.
等等
Wait.
如果你需要个地方住  我随时欢迎你
If you need a place to stay, you're always welcome.
*或许那是软弱的迹象*
*Maybe it's a sign of weakness*
*当我不知该说什么*
*When I don't know what to say*
*或许我就是不知道*
*Maybe I just wouldn't know*
*该如何使用我的力量*
*What to do with my strength anyway*
*我们是否已成习惯*
*Have we become a habit?*
*我们是否扭曲了事实*
*Do we distort the facts?*
*现在没法向前看*
*Now, there's no looking forward*
*没法退后*
*Now, there's no turning back*
*你说我们属于光明*
*When you say we belong to the light*
*我们属于雷电*
*We belong to the thunder*
*我们属于誓言的*
*We belong to the sound of the words*
*声音*
*We've both fallen under*
*不管是否认还是接受*
*Whatever we deny or embrace*
*不管是坏还是好*
*For worse or for better*
*我们是一起的*
*We belong, we belong*
*我们属于彼此*
*We belong together*
*We belong*
*我们属于光明*
*We belong to the light*
*我们属于雷电*
*We belong to the thunder*
怎么回事啊
So...what happened?
我喝了两杯酒
I had two glasses of wine.
那警察显然是罚单没开够
That cop obviously needed to fill his quota --
我们纳的税派上用场了
our tax dollars at work.
但是
But, I mean, um,
你以前从未被开过罚单
you've never even gotten a ticket before.
是啊  现在有了
Yeah, well, now I have.
怎么了
What?
我在想象22岁的自己
I was just picturing my 22-year-old self
走进AGGEK
walking into AGGEK,
拖着交响乐
lugging the Symphonic.
她坐下  开始推介
She sits down, she pitches...
然后我击垮了她
and I crush her.
年轻的我毫无胜算
The young me doesn't stand a chance.
得了
Oh, please.
那个22岁的你也不是单纯无辜
That 22-year-old was hardly sweet and innocent.
现在的你也没那么无情
And the present you isn't so ruthless.
而且那都是你  所有的你
And they're all you, all the versions.
你一直是同一个人
You're the same person that you always were.
而且
And...
我爱那个人
I love that person.
谢谢你让我过来
Thanks for letting me come by.
不客气
Sure.
坐吗
Sit down?
当然了  我们会补偿你
Obviously, we will compensate you.
我觉得我们可以...
I thought we could start --
不必
No need.
不用付费
No payment necessary.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
别担心  我不会告诉乔
Don't worry. I won't tell Joe.
他已经知道了
He already knows.
你没事吧
You okay?
这事谢谢你
Thank you for this.
我不会再来打扰你了
I won't bother you again.
皮特  慢点
Hey, Pete, slow down.
我要去个地方  就回来
I want to make a quick stop.
欢迎来猎狗热狗  需要点什么吗
Welcome to Hound Dogz, can I help you?
嗯  我要...
Yeah, let me get a, uh...
早餐玉米煎饼  和一杯小咖啡
a breakfast burrito and a small coffee.
好的  2.8美元
Yeah, that'll be $2.80.
玉米煎饼和一杯小咖啡  谢谢
Could I get a burrito and a small coffee?
就来
Coming right up.